Branson Lee

🛘 (647) 471-0560 | 🗷 bilee@uwaterloo.ca | 🏕 www.bransonl.com | 🞧 github.com/bransonl | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/bransonl

Summary _

Paradigms 6 years experience with object oriented and 2 years experience with functional programming

Languages Java, Scala, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, C++, Bash, MIPS Assembly, VBA, SQL (Postgres)

Frameworks ¡Query, AngularJS, Node.js, D3.js, Express, Socket.io

Other Tools Unix, Windows, Git, Excel

• Excellent written and oral communication skills demonstrated by preparation of reports as a data analyst

• Adept at learning new languages, frameworks and concepts quickly as exemplified by ability to fluently use Morgan Stanley proprietary frameworks within a short period of time

Experience _

Morgan Stanley

New York City, NY, USA

TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

- Developed data reconciliation application using Scala and Morgan Stanley database APIs, streamlining the firm-wide data model migration process
- Enhanced existing UI application used by traders, improving user experience and developers' ability to debug problems by implementing feature to submit user application logs
- Increased database migration efficiency and accuracy by building a Scala application that queries and manipulates data from multiple data sources to generate clear and detailed progress reports
- Analyzed and prepared reports outlining the impacts of decommissioning legacy classes as part of effort to migrate risk calculation engines to a new framework
- Improved quality of team's code base by tracing, reviewing and making changes to proposed and existing code to better follow code standards

Crown Property Management Inc

Toronto, ON, Canada

DATA ANALYST

May 2015 - Aug 2015

- Increased budgeting productivity by automating data entry tasks using Excel VBA
- Rebuilt data spreadsheets to use Excel VBA and complex formulas to retrieve and organize data from various locations in the company database
- Strengthened written communication and data presentation skills through reorganization of data and preparation of reports for upper management

Projects _

Bulletin 2016

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, D3.JS TREEMAP, ANGULARJS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS

Bulletin board web application that visualizes posts based on importance and grouping using D3.js Treemaps

2 2015

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, ANGULARJS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS, SOCKET.IO

Real-time multiplayer Big 2 web-app with multi-room, chat, spectator and player substitution functionality

alisonlee.co 2015

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT

Portfolio website for designer using client-side JavaScript to generate portfolio structure and content based on contents of folder on server, eliminating the need for knowledge of HTML and CSS to update website content

Education _

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON, Canada

Sep 2014 - Present

CANDIDATE FOR BACHELOR OF COMPUTING AND FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT

• Estimated graduation June 2019